innovation and change are almost a given
in today's
rapidly evolving marketplace what can
organizations do
to enable change and create better
experiences for their customers and
employees
well hello everyone my name is yvonne
chan and joining me in the studio to
discuss
this topic with me today are mr vikesh
sinha the head of operations excellence
at prudential singapore
and miss chitra pranayak the lead
business analyst at kep gemini
singapore welcome vikesh and chitra her
prudential has always been an
organization that puts its customer
well-being at the heart of all that it
does and in this session we want to
focus on what goes on
behind the scenes to ensure that the
entire organization is able to fully
support its customers in enabling
groundbreaking change and innovation and
so i'd like to kick us off with a
question for
vikash about opecs or operational
excellence
tell us what exactly it is and how does
it enable
change and innovation within prudential
thanksgiving for that question
um i mean
in its core it's basically um something
which which helps us to
achieve our purpose potential purpose
which is helping people to make
best out of their life so that's what
opecs is all about
okay we want to really improve
the experience of our customers we want
to drive continuous improvement
and opex helps us or enable us to do
that now how does it do it
we have three pillars of opex that we
call it so the first one is opex academy
which helps to build
the capability of people and improving
and driving continuous improvement
and second one is opex consulting which
basically helps us to execute
any strategic or transformational
projects that we have so we have a pool
of
internal um kind of experts
right who are good in transformation and
driving change projects so they are the
ones who drives this
the third one is something called center
of excellence which basically drives
process automations or automations using
new technologies
okay so that's what opex is and i mean
in summary it is what it is
i just want to add one more thing to
that is opecs
also whatever we do in opex it's it's
about balancing three things
okay number one is voice of the business
okay so our shareholders our
stakeholders whatever they are asking us
to do
uh voice of the customers so whatever
our customers expectations from us
are and the voice of employees the
engagement part okay
so we hear all these three voices and
through opex we try to balance this
so whatever we do in opex is basically
balancing these three voices when we
deliver it
a very good example is in 2019 we rolled
out
a solution called pulse okay which is of
one of our mobile apps
that we rolled out it's been rolled out
in in around 12 countries
and we have almost have the app in like
10 different languages and we i think
till date we have 13 million downloads
okay which which
tells that it's really something which
people are using right
so opecs was also one of the teams which
was working on this
pulse solution and they helped i mean
they basically helped
to make this a reality of translating
whatever the pulse vision was to
to making sure that it is executed in a
way that people wanted and then
rolling it out into the market so
you talked about balancing all these
different components right
using that one common company-wide
methodology and also promoting this
culture i believe of continuous
improvement
chitra is this one of the common
challenges that's faced by the workforce
in the insurance industry you know how
do you still remain staff-centric
when you're faced with a multitude of
systems
so yes that is one of the biggest
challenges right today as a user if i
have to issue a policy
i have to login into a legacy policy
administration system or a document
management system
communicate with my agents and partners
on emails or chats
and uh have communications with my cross
departments
separately yeah so it adds on to your
day-to-day tasks
so we are enabling this change by
building a
one-stop solution wherein the
underwriters can do risk assessment
policies can be issued claims can be
settled
and we can address policy servicing
requests one-stop solution that's the
key word there right so
you guys are coming up with a one-stop
solution to streamline processes and
make
the lives of the employees a lot easier
so this also frees up more of their time
so they get more out of life
before we delve into that one-stop
solution i want to come back to vikash
and ask you about capability building
which i know is really big at prudential
and given that this year's
singapore fintech festival theme centers
around people and talent development
tell me why is capable capability
building so important at prudential and
where
does your opex academy come in see um
one thing which i'm sure everybody would
agree that as we move ahead
and there are certain challenges that we
see right challenging in terms of
the the speed of digitalization today um
the the
change in customer expectations oh yeah
um external factors panadermic
kovit okay which forces us to make those
changes and hence
people cannot have the same capability
and drive those transformation and
changes right
so we need these new skills new
capabilities and
and people have to be ready for that
okay and hence capability becomes
the center piece of it okay people
become the center piece of everything
and within potential uh one of our core
commitment to our people is
capability building right and and we
want to do that
um and and opex academy how do we do it
uh
it's as part of the opex academy we have
three things one
is looking at the quality part of it so
we do it through quality academy which
is
looking at experiences and how to
improve those
experiences okay so that's talks about
the continuous improvement part
yeah the second part is the technical
academy okay which looks at
the core competencies of insurance like
underwriting claims customer service
and looking at where people's learning
cover
and then trying to kind of have programs
across these journeys
where they can improve their skills
right so that's improving the core
insurance skills the third one which is
the most critical one is the digital
academy right everything has to be
digital
and if people have to be and be part of
that digitalization journey
then digital skills become very
important okay so we look at
certain skills which people need for
this digitalization
we try to impart that through the
digital academy
right but the most important part
is is the fundamental of of this whole
opex academy
is it's it's not a training program it's
a experience based learning
okay what does mean is that whatever we
do
okay we first look internally in terms
of whatever people need
right in terms of their learning whether
they're processing a claim so they want
to know more about a claim
if they are doing underwriting so they
want to learn about underwriting
process improvement how to do process
improvement for example so we take these
as training programs we'll build those
training programs
and then we when we deliver this
training program
it is delivered through a kind of an
approach
where people are not only learning the
methodology but as we as they go along
they are adopting it okay right away so
what happens is
um it remains with them yeah the
learnings remains with them it doesn't
just
go away somewhere okay so that's yeah so
let's see
yeah so i mean that's that's the whole
point of
having that academy part which driving
programs
through people okay which they want and
how they want it to be driven
and we just mean it's not too long ago
we launched this academy in jan 2020
and since then we have trained almost
like 300 to 320 people which is
a sizable number if you look at
potential and
the feedback has been great i just want
to get into even more detail now vikash
you know what other ways does opec
drive innovation but at the same time
still making sure that your people and
talent development
remain a top priority yeah so okay
good point innovation i think it's it's
potential is one of
our core value okay and whatever we do
and i talked about the purpose part of
it innovation drives this
okay whatever we do we want to be
innovative in terms of creating
solutions
or creating anything that we want both
for our external customers and internal
right
so in opex what we did was we thought
okay let's create something which helps
us to
look at internally at least our process
and everything and helps
our own staff our own people right
because sometimes they are the most
ignored ones and nobody looks at them
right
so we said okay let's create a center of
excellence with all these new
technologies that we hear about whether
it is
robotics rpa or ai or machine learning
or nlps and there are many more
technologies right um and and
so we created this coe with the idea
that okay let's try it out
okay let's be innovative let's do some
proof of concept and if it works out
let's scale it up let's build that
solution right so that's what
i mean when the whole idea of setting up
that opec coe was
and what happened was when we built up
the coe
we also knew that we have to work and
partner with a lot of this fintechs and
ensure techs
to build and bring in some new solutions
right and that's where we work with
quite a lot of them we rolled out in
2019 itself um
i mean some of the solutions we picked
it up which we rolled out in 2020 like
automating our underwriting engine we
looked at our
claims process and we said okay how do
we make it far more simpler using some
of these new technologies
and many more actually i mean we have
delivered quite a few solutions using
all this ai and and machine learning
processes
but the key one which we rolled out this
year is something called the operations
ecosystem
okay where we want to build an ecosystem
for our own
internal staff which helps them to
simplify their own life
their own processes and look at the
processes as they wanted
okay so that's the automation we wanted
so that they work with one system rather
than with
multiple systems that normally people
work with okay it makes life a lot more
easier too
chitra can we get you to elaborate on a
little bit more on how this
operations ecosystem works because i'm
sure many of the audience today would be
very interested to see
how a solution still manages to be
staff-centric yes
so like because spoke about having
certain objectives behind developing
this solution and one of those key
objectives was to have an interconnected
and an iterative solution providing
real-time data for
monitoring and improvement so imagine
yourself as an underwriter
i have these data-driven dashboards
providing me
with activity insights and a total
visibility on my assigned tasks
i have visibility on the slas which can
help me meet my agency and partner
commitments
the solution is intelligent and
intuitive by telling me where i need to
focus
my priorities for the day so these
priorities uh can be set
based on for example certain campaigns
run by our agents and partners
or addressing our high net worth
customer requests first
it also provides me with the data
wherein i know how much time i'm
spending on each activity
and help me identify my own improvement
areas
right as a team lead i i get the single
view of the team's activity which is
especially useful for me
during the month ends when the volumes
are high right it helps me in load
balancing and making a well-informed
decision
uh one of the other objectives of the
solution was to provide
a rule-driven and a data-driven workflow
wherein i as a user i don't have to be
concerned about the workload being two
more
or maybe the incorrect assignments being
given to me
because the logic at the back end takes
care of your role your activities
your capacity and availability for the
day and one of the biggest advantages of
the solution is that it is built
using the artificial intelligence and
machine learning based algorithms for
data processing data extraction and
validation
and enabling to trigger workflows having
us these touchless operations
right so as a user i get this single
view of the customer
so the solution actually can get or
absorb content
from say a hard copy submission or email
or a mobile upload
right so the solution being integrated
with the multiple applications not only
helps me in making better or faster
decisions
but by predicting and identifying the
bottlenecks i know
where to monitor my process proactively
so
it helps us achieve operational
excellence for our customers people and
partners
that's fantastic it's such a an
intuitive
smart system that really enhances
productivity and like you said
it can't uh imagine it kind of is able
to tell whether you're overloaded
whether you have capacity or not and
capabilities so
on the flip side you can't tell your
boss i have too much work because the
system
would have just allocated what you can
do right so it's super smart i really
like that
but it does also sound uh guys that the
team has achieved a lot in a relatively
short span of time so
uh with more projects in the pipeline
more innovation expected
what what does opex hope to achieve um
no
for 2021 the the plan is to even do more
um especially on improving the staff
experience okay
because what we believe definitely in
opex is that
if you improve the staff work experience
using the the technologies which are
available to them i think
that drives more engagement that drives
more productivity okay productivity may
be
in a wrong i mean it's a wrong
connotation in a way but i would say it
drives more engagement and loyalty
towards the organization
okay because it helps them to make their
life simpler and then the last thing
which
which which is very important for me is
that which i always believed in that
if you really have to win in marketplace
okay we have to first win in the
workplace
if if your people are internally happy
they will always make your customers
happy
okay speaking of your people being
internally happy and having to win
uh in the workplace before you go into
the marketplace i really like that motto
you've put your stuff through uh three
different academies right digital
technical as well as quality did i get
that right
you see i've been paying attention so
you put them through these three
academies what was the feedback
like from your employees well the
feedback has been great one
feedback has been the the difference
they see
from the normal trainings okay like in a
normal training you have
your trainer your slides and your
classroom or your virtual training which
happens these days right
so that's the only the combinations that
you have got and it's all content
content content right
you don't know whether the person who is
actually going through that training
actually understands all of that
right or even takes back anything in
opex whatever we do
first of all we look at the real
problems we look at what people want our
staff wants
and which can help us to drive that
mindset of continuous improvement
and improving customer experience and
all of that okay so what is the
requirement first okay what the people
need
so we take those and we develop certain
programs like in quality management or
technical or digital
once that is done we develop life
projects or real life student
simulations
which basically people can actually
apply it while they learn it
so most of the programs that we offer it
could be a one day program or a two day
or a five day
program but most of this are delivered
through an actual project
okay where people can actually adopt
whatever they have learned
and hence they have been their feedback
has been great they say okay something
which when i go out even after five days
i will remember it forever okay so it's
very hands-on
very handsome right and it's not like
you said just a textbook learning that
it's just one-sided but it's two-sided
as well
for a question for the both of you then
do you have um any words of advice you
know for fintech firms who are
or maybe non-fiction tech firms who are
watching today and who might you know be
really impressed with how this opex
academy is working and they might want
to adopt
a similar fintech solution but they have
reservations
about embarking on this approach which
is rather out of the box what would you
say to them let's start with you chitra
i would echo what vikas said earlier
about putting your people first
at the backdrop of having an end-to-end
transformation
so i think giving the key value
proposition to your workforce is
extremely important
in helping you also win your customers
and in the end
yeah i know no i
definitely echo that for me what is
important is
um that we talk about our customers
okay we talk about their ecosystem we
talk about our distributors and their
ecosystems
but we never talk about our people who
are in the back end actually who are
doing the work okay and and we never
talk about their ecosystem because they
also have to work with multiple systems
how do we connect all of that okay how
do we bring that together so that at
least we make their life even better
yeah so that is something which is very
very important right so hence
we i mean the whole point of creating
this operations ecosystem was that
how do i bring that little things with
people do using
system one two three and four how do i
merge all of this one two three four
into something
which not only solves their problem in
terms of the automation problem but
also it gives them they should feel it
that
this is a system which listens to me
rather than i have to learn the solution
and then
do the do their work okay that's
something which is important so this
ties back into how a solution still
manages to be a system or a solution
manages to be staff-centric
and just before we conclude uh because i
have both of you in the hot seat right
now quick question for you
because you said don't forget the people
who are putting this together right have
you
been through uh any of the academies
under the
opex academy the digital technical and
quality quality that's right which ones
really stood out for you which ones do
you like
for me a digital one is important i mean
all three are important you know equally
but digital is important because of the
the kind of transformation today happens
and especially the speed of
transformation right
and and it's all about digitalization um
and
because of the pandemic because of kobe
also some of these things have
accelerated a little bit yeah so people
need to learn the basic skills of
digitalization right so hence digital
becomes
very important but equally technical if
you
i mean we are in insurance so we also
need to improve our underwriting and
claims and everything and similarly
if you have to create new experience
then quality becomes important right so
so you can have one without the other
one right right the cash what about you
chitra
i i think i would go with both digital
and the technology academies
because i think it it definitely helps
us do our jobs better
and it does sound you know so exciting
so much to look forward to
and i do believe that you know the
projects that opec is involved in will
certainly bring about the change that is
required
for an organization to stay relevant in
these ever-changing times
you can find out more about one of the
projects that opex was involved in by
scanning this qr code to download
pulse till next time a big thank you
again to mr vikashinda
and miss chitra pranayak for joining us
in the studio my name is yvonne chan
stay well and i'll see you next time